<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deals-Central PwC</title>
	<atom:link href="//deals-central.pwc.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:09:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pak student secures top spot in Audit &#038; Assurance</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/pak-student-secures-top-spot-in-audit-assurance/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/pak-student-secures-top-spot-in-audit-assurance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assurance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ACCA has announced the results for students who took their exams in September 2023. A...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/pak-student-secures-top-spot-in-audit-assurance/">Pak student secures top spot in Audit &#038; Assurance</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ACCA has announced the results for students who took their exams in September 2023. A thousands of students from across the globe participated in the October session of ACCA exams.</p>
<p>Ibad Haseeb from Karachi has landed the top spot with the highest scores in Audit and Assurance (AA) making him the prize-winner. This distinction is a notable achievement and highlights Ibad’s commitment towards creating a strong career for himself in the field of accountancy.</p>
<p>Assad Hameed Khan, Head of ACCA Pakistan, commented: “We are always proud to see our Pakistani students receive worldwide distinctions. This highlights the untapped potential within this nation’s youth that ACCA is dedicated to polishing and enabling them to pursue successful careers within and outside of Pakistan. Our youth faces a plethora of adversities and its through achievements such as Ibad’s that we see that it only enables them to shine brighter.”</p>
<p>Ibad attributes his success to relentless hard work and unwavering perseverance. He expresses gratitude for the unwavering support he received from his parents and educators at Tabani’s School of Accountancy (TSA), notably he thanks Haris Hanif, who tutored him for AA.</p>
<p>Ibad shares, “When I first started prepping, I made numerous errors and mistakes but it was only through constant dedication and practice that I was able to build my confidence up and attempt the challenge.”</p>
<p>The ACCA qualification commands substantial recognition and enjoys widespread recognition on a global scale, thereby presenting captivating career prospects with prominent employers. The ACCA Qualification meticulously evaluates the skills, capabilities, and competencies requisite for a contemporary accountant, all while fostering a strong foundation in ethics and professionalism.</p>
<p>ACCA stands as the world’s premier institution for professional accountants, boasting a membership of 247,000 and a prospective membership of 542,000 hailing from 178 countries and regions.</p>
<p>Copyright Business Recorder, 2023</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/pak-student-secures-top-spot-in-audit-assurance/">Pak student secures top spot in Audit &#038; Assurance</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/pak-student-secures-top-spot-in-audit-assurance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enhancing interconnectedness for audit teams and clients</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/enhancing-interconnectedness-for-audit-teams-and-clients/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/enhancing-interconnectedness-for-audit-teams-and-clients/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enhancing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>New digital tools are transforming the way auditors and clients work, with greater collaboration and...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/enhancing-interconnectedness-for-audit-teams-and-clients/">Enhancing interconnectedness for audit teams and clients</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New digital tools are transforming the way auditors and clients work, with greater collaboration and frictionless workflow heralding a new audit journey.</p>
<p>The landscape of audit technology has changed beyond all recognition in recent years. With the emergence of AI and machine learning the promises being made by enthusiastic vendors are becoming increasingly bullish. Whether it’s boosting efficiency or enhancing audit quality, tech tools are essential to the modern audit firm.</p>
<p>“Computed-assisted audit techniques (CAATs) aren’t new,” says PwC’s digital audit leader, Marc Bena. “However, what’s different now is the ease with which people can extract and analyse data and render it all the way through the financial audit in tools like [cloud-based analytics platform] Alteryx, where they can do quite complex modelling and visualisation.”</p>
<p>Indeed, many firms are training their entire workforces in new data tools. Bena says that PwC has trained 5,000 people on Alteryx to help them with data analysis and visualisation. “That’s been the base technology for all our financial auditors, and my data team now has access to our data lake in order to do the more advanced audit techniques,” he says.</p>
<p>Over the past five years most large audit firms have been investing billions in technology and training throughout their organisations in data analysis and AI tools, transforming how they operate.</p>
<p>Making waves<br />
Audit tech efficiency is no longer just the preserve of large audit firms either. All sizes of audit firms are embarking on a similar journey, embedding new tools into the audit process – to ensure the audit workflow process is quicker and smarter.</p>
<p>James Hadfield, a partner and Head of Audit at Top 30 firm Menzies, says that AI in particular is beginning to have an impact in audit workflow: “It’s been around in the background for a long time, even since CAATs. But in the last five years it’s really started to get traction and we’re all now seeing it as a necessary part of what we’re doing.”</p>
<p>Getting clients on board is crucial to improving collaboration. Hadfield says his clients tend to be receptive to process change if his audit teams lead by setting up both sides on the portal, which instantly improves understanding and workflow.</p>
<p>Hadfield is an enthusiastic user of Inflo – an audit workflow tool set up by two former PwC accountants. “We use it in a few ways. The first is the client portal, which helps us exchange data. Given that most client data is in digital form, it allows us to upload big data sets and what’s great is how organised it is. Auditors can set up requests for what you need, assign responsibilities, put in due dates and track the progress of the job, which is extremely helpful.”</p>
<p>And since COVID-19, Hadfield says tools that facilitate better collaboration such as Inflo have helped with remote working: “Without the portal you’re reliant on email and Dropbox, where things can get lost or muddled. Being organised is really crucial to a well delivered audit.”</p>
<p>As Menzies’ audit teams begin to harvest the benefits of improved digital efficiencies, Hadfield says increasingly the focus has switched to improving quality. “The other modules in Inflo are data and analytics led, and you can import complete datasets from the client – so for instance we can import the entire general ledger for the year, giving us every single transaction that’s been posted.</p>
<p>“And from that, by using defined risk parameters in the software, we can get to individual journal entries that we want to look at,” he explains. “There might be an error or fraud, and whereas previously we’d have an Excel download or a massive, printed journal, trying to shoot into that like a sniper isn’t the same as interrogating every single transaction. So that’s a big thing that analytics lets us do.”</p>
<p>Interconnected</p>
<p>James Berridge at Saffery Champness agrees that workflow tools are having a big impact on how his firm delivers its audit services. The firms started using Inflo in the autumn last year.</p>
<p>In the audit space, one of the things Berridge says he’s keen to assess focuses on how its internal systems can be linked together from a data quality and efficiency standpoint. Once they’re linked, he says it becomes much easier to tie everything together. At that point, he says auditors can then say: “We’re getting a lot of our general ledger information by Inflo so let’s pull that in and have that tied in with our practice management system.”</p>
<p>Berridge adds: “That will allow us to identify the client ID and how that relates to this general ledger information from this period. We can start to then push through the likes of Power BI and start to visualise the client’s data – and that allows us to pull out the nuances that we want, rather than the information that Inflo thinks is relevant to auditors.”</p>
<p>The key, then, he says is to reduce data overload – and auditor burnout – which is a big selling point of perhaps the most widely used AI-led audit tool, DataSnipper. Developed as an Excel-hosted intelligent audit platform, it has already been adopted by Big Four firms and smaller firms alike.</p>
<p>Berridge says DataSnipper’s ability to extract data from a PDF, for instance, can be useful when the client sends data in a less-than-ideal format.</p>
<p>“But also, it has an automated document-matching feature. So if you know what you’re looking for when you’re doing expenses testing, such as the invoice number, the amount, the date – and hopefully in the big pile of invoices there sits the correct one – DataSnipper will find and report it for you; and it will highlight on the document where it was.</p>
<p>By speeding up the process documentation, Berridge says clients are brought on board and can collaborate far more effectively. “Now, instead of searching through 100 terribly named documents, you can say: ‘This is my data point, these are the files, I want to match it to bank statements,’ and it’ll match it to that as well. If you click on the cells, because it shows you the right document and the right bit, that’s effectively when you start your work. It’s all pre-documented and you’re basically verifying what it’s found for you. It’s a massive time-saver and really helpful for work flow.”</p>
<p>Indeed, one of the biggest challenges for auditors is extracting data from clients’ systems. “That’s tough because every system is different and each client has it configured in different ways,” Menzies’s Hadfield says.</p>
<p>As analytics and other software evolves however, so too does clients’ software. “We’ll get to a point when it’ll be a more seamless process. For me that’ll be the watershed moment because the challenge of getting data information from the clients will be gone and it’ll all be there for you at the click of a button.”</p>
<p>Greater collaboration<br />
As collaboration improves and work flows become more frictionless, the ability to apply scepticism will also come to fore, says Tom Allison, associate director at Buzzacott. He says the impact of tools like E-circu, a French-built platform for customer and supplier confirmations and bank confirmations, will eliminate human interference before the data reaches the audit team, and allow more time for holistic judgement.</p>
<p>“Back in the old days you’d write to the supplier and they would post you the relevant documents. No-one does that any more due to the poor response rate,” he says.</p>
<p>Today, open banking confirmation tools provide that extra layer of assurance as well as speed and efficiency, which promises to save substantial time in an auditor’s day and eliminate the humdrum side of auditing.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/enhancing-interconnectedness-for-audit-teams-and-clients/">Enhancing interconnectedness for audit teams and clients</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/enhancing-interconnectedness-for-audit-teams-and-clients/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Single financial reporting body to be formed</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/single-financial-reporting-body-to-be-formed/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/single-financial-reporting-body-to-be-formed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=31</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The federal government has announced its intention to combine three existing financial reporting bodies into...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/single-financial-reporting-body-to-be-formed/">Single financial reporting body to be formed</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The federal government has announced its intention to combine three existing financial reporting bodies into one entity in a move designed to assist the country in implementing new climate and sustainability standards.</p>
<p>Under the proposal, the three financial reporting bodies, being the Australian Accounting Standards Board, Auditing and Assurance Standards Board and Financial Reporting Council, will be amalgamated into one unit.</p>
<p>“In addition to accounting and auditing standards, this new integrated body will better support the ongoing implementation of climate‑related financial disclosure standards in Australia. It is intended that the body will be operational on or after 1 July 2026, subject to the passage of legislation,” Treasurer Jim Chalmers noted.</p>
<p>“Business, investors and other stakeholders will benefit from engaging with a single entity, helping to increase regulatory consistency, reduce red tape and unnecessary costs and avoid duplication.”</p>
<p>The government confirmed the Auditing and Assurance Standards Board will continue its current work on climate‑related financial disclosure standards.</p>
<p>Details of the governance arrangements for the new entity are in the process of being finalised and draft legislation will subsequently be released covering implementation of the measure, including an industry consultation period.</p>
<p>However, the government has already received criticism regarding the consultation process associated with the initiative.</p>
<p>To this end, Chartered Accountants Australia and New Zealand (CAANZ) advocacy and international development group executive Simon Grant suggested consultation for the measure has not been broad enough.</p>
<p>“While it is good to see concerted efforts and focus on implementing important climate and sustainability standards – something we have consistently shown a willingness to work with the government on – we are disappointed the announcement was made without effective profession, industry and capital markets consultation,” Grant said.</p>
<p>Specifically, he expressed his concerns around a lack of detail as to Australia’s alignment to international accounting, audit and sustainability standards setters, and how the move will be funded.</p>
<p>“CAANZ and many other stakeholders have urged the government to establish a focused sustainability standards board to have the right expertise and international alignment from the outset,” he noted.</p>
<p>“Today’s announcement is the largest reform to the accounting and audit standard setting bodies in decades and yet it was revealed via a speech in a public forum.”</p>
<p>The criticism follows concerns expressed by a group of joint bodies covering financial advice and tax professionals as to amendments pertaining to the reporting of breaches of the Code of Professional Conduct in the Tax Agent Services Act 2009.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/single-financial-reporting-body-to-be-formed/">Single financial reporting body to be formed</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/single-financial-reporting-body-to-be-formed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Accountants deserve detail on proposed merger of oversight bodies: Taylor</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accountants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Shadow treasurer Angus Taylor has slammed treasurer Jim Chalmers for failing to properly consult professional...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/">Accountants deserve detail on proposed merger of oversight bodies: Taylor</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shadow treasurer Angus Taylor has slammed treasurer Jim Chalmers for failing to properly consult professional accounting bodies prior to announcing the Albanese government’s policy to have a ‘one-stop’ shop for standard setting.</p>
<p>Taylor told The Mandarin the coalition supported the overall policy of regulatory simplification and that the coalition will review any legislative proposal to merge the Financial Reporting Council, the Australian Accounting Standards Board, and the Auditing and Assurance Standards Board.</p>
<p>This proposal is the first significant change to the standard-setting structure since the Howard government brought accounting standard-setting in its completeness into the public sector in 2000 with audit standard-setting following sometime after.</p>
<p>The proposal, announced by Chalmers last week, was flagged the day before to the affected standard seters but the professional accounting bodies that have had a history of stewardship of standard setting were not alerted beforehand.</p>
<p>“While the Coalition supports the principle of regulatory simplification, the Coalition are concerned by further reports that many key stakeholders were not consulted on this measure, and first found out about it when it was announced in the media,” Taylor said.</p>
<p>“This is not what good government looks like and is becoming a feature of this government’s approach to the Treasury portfolio.”</p>
<p>“There are thousands of professionals across the accounting, audit and assurance industries — they deserve more detail about substantial changes to the way their profession is governed and operates.”</p>
<p>Taylor’s remarks follow a media release issued by the Chartered Accountants — Australia and New Zealand after the announcement pointing to the absence of consultation with the accounting profession.</p>
<p>“While it is good to see concerted efforts and focus on implementing important climate and sustainability standards — something we have consistently shown a willingness to work with the Government on ––we are disappointed the announcement was made without effective profession, industry and capital markets consultation,” Simon Grant, CA ANZ’s Group Executive Advocacy and International Development, said.</p>
<p>The federal government said that it intends to engage in consultation before it gets legislation before parliament.</p>
<p>A new merged structure could be in place by the middle of 2026.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/">Accountants deserve detail on proposed merger of oversight bodies: Taylor</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Audit: What It Means in Finance and Accounting, and 3 Main Types</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What Is an Audit? The term audit usually refers to the financial audit or review...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/">Audit: What It Means in Finance and Accounting, and 3 Main Types</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What Is an Audit?<br />
The term audit usually refers to the financial audit or review of financial statements. A financial audit is an objective examination and evaluation of the financial statements of an organization to make sure that the financial records are a fair and accurate representation of the transactions they claim to represent. The audit can be conducted internally by employees of the organization or externally by an outside certified public accountant (CPA) firm.</p>
<p>KEY TAKEAWAYS<br />
There are three main types of audits: external audits, internal audits, and Internal Revenue Service audits.<br />
External audits are commonly performed by Certified Public Accounting firms and result in an auditor&#8217;s opinion which is included in the audit report.<br />
An unqualified, or clean, audit opinion means that the auditor has not identified any material misstatement as a result of his or her review of the financial statements.</p>
<p>Understanding Audits<br />
An audit is the review or inspection of a company or individual&#8217;s accounts by an independent body. Auditors may be hired internally by the company or work for an external third-party firm. Almost all companies receive a yearly audit of their financial statements. This includes the review of statements like the income statement, balance sheet, and cash flow statement.</p>
<p>Lenders often require the results of an external audit annually as part of their debt covenants. For some companies, audits are a legal requirement due to the compelling incentives to intentionally misstate financial information in an attempt to commit fraud. As a result of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002, publicly traded companies must also receive an evaluation of the effectiveness of their internal controls.1</p>
<p>Standards for external audits performed in the United States, called the generally accepted auditing standards (GAAS), are set out by the Auditing Standards Board (ASB) of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA).2</p>
<p>Additional rules for the audits of publicly traded companies are made by the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB), which was established as a result of SOX in 2002.3 A separate set of international standards, which are called the International Standards on Auditing, was set up by the International Auditing and Assurance Standards Board.4</p>
<p>Importance of Audits<br />
Audits are a necessary and important part of the financial world. That&#8217;s because a company&#8217;s financial health and well-being can&#8217;t be upheld without proper accounting. Routine audits ensure that companies are following reporting standards and, more importantly, that they are being truthful and honest about their financial position. Audits are particularly important for shareholders and lenders as well as consumers and suppliers.</p>
<p>The process of auditing also helps companies in other ways, including:</p>
<p>Finding inefficiencies<br />
Improving production and operations<br />
Meeting compliance requirements<br />
Establishing procedures for monitoring<br />
Fraud prevention<br />
Types of Audits<br />
Audits can involve financial accounts of companies or individuals. They can be conducted by external or internal auditors, and may also be completed by taxation agencies like the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).</p>
<p>External Audits<br />
Unqualified audits performed by outside parties can be extremely helpful in removing any bias in reviewing the state of a company&#8217;s financials. Financial audits seek to identify if there are any material misstatements in the financial statements.</p>
<p>An unqualified, or clean, auditor&#8217;s opinion provides financial statement users with confidence that the financials are both accurate and complete. External audits, therefore, allow stakeholders to make better, more informed decisions related to the company being audited.</p>
<p>External auditors follow a set of standards that are different from those of the company or organization hiring them to do the work. When audits are performed by third parties, the resulting auditor&#8217;s opinion expressed on items being audited (a company&#8217;s financials, internal controls, or a system) can be candid and honest without affecting daily work relationships within the company.</p>
<p>Internal Audits<br />
Internal auditors are employed by the company or organization for whom they are performing an audit, and the resulting audit report is given directly to management and the board of directors.</p>
<p>Consultant auditors, while not employed internally, use the standards of the company they are auditing as opposed to a separate set of standards. Internal auditors are used when an organization doesn’t have the in-house resources to audit certain parts of its own operations.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/">Audit: What It Means in Finance and Accounting, and 3 Main Types</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
