<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Accountants Archives - Deals-Central PwC</title>
	<atom:link href="//deals-central.pwc.com/tag/accountants/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/tag/accountants/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:05:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Accountants deserve detail on proposed merger of oversight bodies: Taylor</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accountants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Shadow treasurer Angus Taylor has slammed treasurer Jim Chalmers for failing to properly consult professional...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/">Accountants deserve detail on proposed merger of oversight bodies: Taylor</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shadow treasurer Angus Taylor has slammed treasurer Jim Chalmers for failing to properly consult professional accounting bodies prior to announcing the Albanese government’s policy to have a ‘one-stop’ shop for standard setting.</p>
<p>Taylor told The Mandarin the coalition supported the overall policy of regulatory simplification and that the coalition will review any legislative proposal to merge the Financial Reporting Council, the Australian Accounting Standards Board, and the Auditing and Assurance Standards Board.</p>
<p>This proposal is the first significant change to the standard-setting structure since the Howard government brought accounting standard-setting in its completeness into the public sector in 2000 with audit standard-setting following sometime after.</p>
<p>The proposal, announced by Chalmers last week, was flagged the day before to the affected standard seters but the professional accounting bodies that have had a history of stewardship of standard setting were not alerted beforehand.</p>
<p>“While the Coalition supports the principle of regulatory simplification, the Coalition are concerned by further reports that many key stakeholders were not consulted on this measure, and first found out about it when it was announced in the media,” Taylor said.</p>
<p>“This is not what good government looks like and is becoming a feature of this government’s approach to the Treasury portfolio.”</p>
<p>“There are thousands of professionals across the accounting, audit and assurance industries — they deserve more detail about substantial changes to the way their profession is governed and operates.”</p>
<p>Taylor’s remarks follow a media release issued by the Chartered Accountants — Australia and New Zealand after the announcement pointing to the absence of consultation with the accounting profession.</p>
<p>“While it is good to see concerted efforts and focus on implementing important climate and sustainability standards — something we have consistently shown a willingness to work with the Government on ––we are disappointed the announcement was made without effective profession, industry and capital markets consultation,” Simon Grant, CA ANZ’s Group Executive Advocacy and International Development, said.</p>
<p>The federal government said that it intends to engage in consultation before it gets legislation before parliament.</p>
<p>A new merged structure could be in place by the middle of 2026.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/">Accountants deserve detail on proposed merger of oversight bodies: Taylor</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/accountants-deserve-detail-on-proposed-merger-of-oversight-bodies-taylor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
