<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Audit Archives - Deals-Central PwC</title>
	<atom:link href="//deals-central.pwc.com/tag/audit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/tag/audit/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:04:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Audit: What It Means in Finance and Accounting, and 3 Main Types</title>
		<link>//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/</link>
					<comments>//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pwc]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 22:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">//deals-central.pwc.com/?p=25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What Is an Audit? The term audit usually refers to the financial audit or review...</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/">Audit: What It Means in Finance and Accounting, and 3 Main Types</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What Is an Audit?<br />
The term audit usually refers to the financial audit or review of financial statements. A financial audit is an objective examination and evaluation of the financial statements of an organization to make sure that the financial records are a fair and accurate representation of the transactions they claim to represent. The audit can be conducted internally by employees of the organization or externally by an outside certified public accountant (CPA) firm.</p>
<p>KEY TAKEAWAYS<br />
There are three main types of audits: external audits, internal audits, and Internal Revenue Service audits.<br />
External audits are commonly performed by Certified Public Accounting firms and result in an auditor&#8217;s opinion which is included in the audit report.<br />
An unqualified, or clean, audit opinion means that the auditor has not identified any material misstatement as a result of his or her review of the financial statements.</p>
<p>Understanding Audits<br />
An audit is the review or inspection of a company or individual&#8217;s accounts by an independent body. Auditors may be hired internally by the company or work for an external third-party firm. Almost all companies receive a yearly audit of their financial statements. This includes the review of statements like the income statement, balance sheet, and cash flow statement.</p>
<p>Lenders often require the results of an external audit annually as part of their debt covenants. For some companies, audits are a legal requirement due to the compelling incentives to intentionally misstate financial information in an attempt to commit fraud. As a result of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002, publicly traded companies must also receive an evaluation of the effectiveness of their internal controls.1</p>
<p>Standards for external audits performed in the United States, called the generally accepted auditing standards (GAAS), are set out by the Auditing Standards Board (ASB) of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA).2</p>
<p>Additional rules for the audits of publicly traded companies are made by the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB), which was established as a result of SOX in 2002.3 A separate set of international standards, which are called the International Standards on Auditing, was set up by the International Auditing and Assurance Standards Board.4</p>
<p>Importance of Audits<br />
Audits are a necessary and important part of the financial world. That&#8217;s because a company&#8217;s financial health and well-being can&#8217;t be upheld without proper accounting. Routine audits ensure that companies are following reporting standards and, more importantly, that they are being truthful and honest about their financial position. Audits are particularly important for shareholders and lenders as well as consumers and suppliers.</p>
<p>The process of auditing also helps companies in other ways, including:</p>
<p>Finding inefficiencies<br />
Improving production and operations<br />
Meeting compliance requirements<br />
Establishing procedures for monitoring<br />
Fraud prevention<br />
Types of Audits<br />
Audits can involve financial accounts of companies or individuals. They can be conducted by external or internal auditors, and may also be completed by taxation agencies like the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).</p>
<p>External Audits<br />
Unqualified audits performed by outside parties can be extremely helpful in removing any bias in reviewing the state of a company&#8217;s financials. Financial audits seek to identify if there are any material misstatements in the financial statements.</p>
<p>An unqualified, or clean, auditor&#8217;s opinion provides financial statement users with confidence that the financials are both accurate and complete. External audits, therefore, allow stakeholders to make better, more informed decisions related to the company being audited.</p>
<p>External auditors follow a set of standards that are different from those of the company or organization hiring them to do the work. When audits are performed by third parties, the resulting auditor&#8217;s opinion expressed on items being audited (a company&#8217;s financials, internal controls, or a system) can be candid and honest without affecting daily work relationships within the company.</p>
<p>Internal Audits<br />
Internal auditors are employed by the company or organization for whom they are performing an audit, and the resulting audit report is given directly to management and the board of directors.</p>
<p>Consultant auditors, while not employed internally, use the standards of the company they are auditing as opposed to a separate set of standards. Internal auditors are used when an organization doesn’t have the in-house resources to audit certain parts of its own operations.</p>
<p>The post <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/">Audit: What It Means in Finance and Accounting, and 3 Main Types</a> appeared first on <a href="//deals-central.pwc.com">Deals-Central PwC</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>//deals-central.pwc.com/audit-what-it-means-in-finance-and-accounting-and-3-main-types/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
